"use strict";(self.webpackChunksharek_dev=self.webpackChunksharek_dev||[]).push([[7276],{3905:(e,t,a)=>{a.d(t,{Zo:()=>m,kt:()=>u});var n=a(7294);function r(e,t,a){return t in e?Object.defineProperty(e,t,{value:a,enumerable:!0,configurable:!0,writable:!0}):e[t]=a,e}function p(e,t){var a=Object.keys(e);if(Object.getOwnPropertySymbols){var n=Object.getOwnPropertySymbols(e);t&&(n=n.filter((function(t){return Object.getOwnPropertyDescriptor(e,t).enumerable}))),a.push.apply(a,n)}return a}function i(e){for(var t=1;t<arguments.length;t++){var a=null!=arguments[t]?arguments[t]:{};t%2?p(Object(a),!0).forEach((function(t){r(e,t,a[t])})):Object.getOwnPropertyDescriptors?Object.defineProperties(e,Object.getOwnPropertyDescriptors(a)):p(Object(a)).forEach((function(t){Object.defineProperty(e,t,Object.getOwnPropertyDescriptor(a,t))}))}return e}function o(e,t){if(null==e)return{};var a,n,r=function(e,t){if(null==e)return{};var a,n,r={},p=Object.keys(e);for(n=0;n<p.length;n++)a=p[n],t.indexOf(a)>=0||(r[a]=e[a]);return r}(e,t);if(Object.getOwnPropertySymbols){var p=Object.getOwnPropertySymbols(e);for(n=0;n<p.length;n++)a=p[n],t.indexOf(a)>=0||Object.prototype.propertyIsEnumerable.call(e,a)&&(r[a]=e[a])}return r}var s=n.createContext({}),l=function(e){var t=n.useContext(s),a=t;return e&&(a="function"==typeof e?e(t):i(i({},t),e)),a},m=function(e){var t=l(e.components);return n.createElement(s.Provider,{value:t},e.children)},k="mdxType",c={inlineCode:"code",wrapper:function(e){var t=e.children;return n.createElement(n.Fragment,{},t)}},N=n.forwardRef((function(e,t){var a=e.components,r=e.mdxType,p=e.originalType,s=e.parentName,m=o(e,["components","mdxType","originalType","parentName"]),k=l(a),N=r,u=k["".concat(s,".").concat(N)]||k[N]||c[N]||p;return a?n.createElement(u,i(i({ref:t},m),{},{components:a})):n.createElement(u,i({ref:t},m))}));function u(e,t){var a=arguments,r=t&&t.mdxType;if("string"==typeof e||r){var p=a.length,i=new Array(p);i[0]=N;var o={};for(var s in t)hasOwnProperty.call(t,s)&&(o[s]=t[s]);o.originalType=e,o[k]="string"==typeof e?e:r,i[1]=o;for(var l=2;l<p;l++)i[l]=a[l];return n.createElement.apply(null,i)}return n.createElement.apply(null,a)}N.displayName="MDXCreateElement"},7938:(e,t,a)=>{a.r(t),a.d(t,{assets:()=>s,contentTitle:()=>i,default:()=>c,frontMatter:()=>p,metadata:()=>o,toc:()=>l});var n=a(7462),r=(a(7294),a(3905));const p={title:"Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark Exam questions"},i=void 0,o={unversionedId:"spark/articles/databricks-spark-developer-associate-exam",id:"spark/articles/databricks-spark-developer-associate-exam",title:"Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark Exam questions",description:"Here are 30 example questions for the Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark certification exam, along with their answers:",source:"@site/sections/data_processing/spark/06-articles/databricks-spark-developer-associate-exam.md",sourceDirName:"spark/06-articles",slug:"/spark/articles/databricks-spark-developer-associate-exam",permalink:"/data_processing/spark/articles/databricks-spark-developer-associate-exam",draft:!1,tags:[],version:"current",frontMatter:{title:"Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark Exam questions"},sidebar:"docs",previous:{title:"Host your own Spark cluster",permalink:"/data_processing/spark/tutorials/setup_standalone_cluster"},next:{title:"Exploring the Exciting New Features in Apache Spark 3.0",permalink:"/data_processing/spark/articles/whats-new-in-spark3"}},s={},l=[],m={toc:l},k="wrapper";function c(e){let{components:t,...a}=e;return(0,r.kt)(k,(0,n.Z)({},m,a,{components:t,mdxType:"MDXLayout"}),(0,r.kt)("p",null,"Here are 30 example questions for the Databricks Certified Associate Developer for Apache Spark certification exam, along with their answers:"),(0,r.kt)("ol",null,(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is Apache Spark's primary abstraction for working with structured data?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," DataFrame")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which programming languages are officially supported by Apache Spark?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Scala, Python, Java, and R")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the fundamental unit of data in Spark, represented as an immutable distributed collection of objects?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Resilient Distributed Dataset (RDD)")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark component is responsible for managing the execution of tasks in a parallel and fault-tolerant manner?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Spark Core")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which operation in Spark allows you to transform an RDD into another RDD by applying a function to each element?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"map"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which transformation operation in Spark returns a new RDD containing only the elements that satisfy a given condition?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"filter"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the purpose of the ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"groupBy")," transformation in Spark?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It groups elements in an RDD based on a key and applies a function to each group.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark transformation allows you to perform an aggregation across all elements of an RDD?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"reduce"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the primary advantage of using DataFrames over RDDs in Spark?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," DataFrames offer better optimization and execution performance due to their schema information.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark operation is used to join two DataFrames based on a common column?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"join"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," In Spark, what is the purpose of a broadcast variable?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It allows you to efficiently distribute a read-only value to worker nodes.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which operation in Spark returns the first element of an RDD?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"first"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which transformation in Spark flattens a nested structure by turning it into a flat list?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"flatMap"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the Spark SQL API used for?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It provides a way to work with structured data using SQL queries or DataFrame operations.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark transformation is used to sample data from an RDD?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"sample"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the purpose of the ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"distinct")," transformation in Spark?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It returns a new RDD containing distinct elements of the original RDD.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:"),' In Spark, what does "lazy evaluation" mean?'),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Transformations on RDDs are not executed immediately but only when an action is called.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark action returns the number of elements in an RDD?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"count"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the difference between ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"cache")," and ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"persist")," operations in Spark?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Both store RDD in memory, but ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"persist")," allows you to specify storage level.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which action in Spark returns a new RDD containing all elements of the source RDD in random order?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"repartition"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the purpose of the ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"union")," transformation in Spark?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It combines two RDDs to create a new RDD containing all elements from both RDDs.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which transformation in Spark returns a new RDD by applying a function to each partition?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"mapPartitions"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What does the ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"collect")," action in Spark do?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It retrieves all elements of an RDD and brings them to the driver program.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," In Spark, what is the purpose of the ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"take")," action?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It returns the first n elements of an RDD as an array.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which transformation operation in Spark groups elements of an RDD by key and applies an aggregation function?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"reduceByKey"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the main advantage of using DataFrames over RDDs for structured data processing?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," DataFrames allow Spark to optimize query execution and offer better performance.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the key difference between a transformation and an action in Spark?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," Transformations create a new RDD from an existing one, while actions return a value or write data.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which action in Spark returns a new RDD containing a specified number of elements from the beginning?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"take"))),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," What is the purpose of the ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"sortBy")," transformation in Spark?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," It sorts the elements of an RDD based on a key.")),(0,r.kt)("li",{parentName:"ol"},(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Question:")," Which Spark transformation operation is used to filter an RDD by applying a function to each element?"),(0,r.kt)("p",{parentName:"li"},(0,r.kt)("strong",{parentName:"p"},"Answer:")," ",(0,r.kt)("inlineCode",{parentName:"p"},"filter")))))}c.isMDXComponent=!0}}]);